timber.io 2019-10-20

# Privacy Policy | Timber.io

### Introduction

Timber Technologies, Inc. ("Company", "we" or "us"), respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy. This policy describes our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing information that we collect from you or that you provide to us when you visit our site, (our "Site"), use our licensed software (the "Licensed Software"), or use any other products and services made available by us (collectively with the Site and the Licensed Software, the "Services").

Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. By accessing or using the Services, you agree to this Privacy Policy. If you are using the Services on behalf of an entity, you are agreeing to this Privacy Policy for that entity and are representing to us that you have the authority to do so (in which case "you" will refer to that entity). If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use the Services.

### Changes to the Privacy Policy

This policy may change from time to time. If we make any changes, we will post the changes on this page and indicate at the top of this page the date this policy was last revised. We will also notify you of any material changes either through a pop-up notice, e-mail or through other reasonable means. Any such changes are effective immediately when we post them, and apply to all access to and use of the Services thereafter. Your continued use of the Services after the date any such changes become effective constitutes your acceptance of the new policy. You are expected to check this page from time to time so you are aware of any changes.

### Information We Collect and How We Collect Information

This policy sets out what personal data we might collect, how we process and protect that data and the lawful grounds for that processing. In most cases, the lawful ground will be that the processing: (i) is necessary for our legitimate interests in carrying out our business, including to grow and improve our Services, provided those interests are not outweighed by your rights and interests (“Legitimate Interests”), (ii) is necessary to perform a contract with you (“Contract”), or (iii) we have a legal obligation to carry out the processing (“Legal Obligation”). Where processing is based on your consent (“Consent”), we will identify the processing purposes and provide you with relevant information to make the processing fair and transparent.

The information we collect from you falls into two categories: personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") and non-personally identifiable information (i.e., information that cannot be used to identify who you are) ("Non-Personal Information"). Below are the various ways in which we may collect Personal Information and Non-Personal information from you.

Information We Automatically Collect. We and third-party service providers acting on our behalf, which may include third-party analytics service providers and third-party advertisers, may incorporate technology such as "pixel tags", "web beacons", and "cookies" that allow us to track the actions of users of our Services automatically. For example, we may automatically collect your location information, information about your internet connection, browser information, information about when you access the Services, the website address that linked you to our Site, the website that you visit after using our Services, and details of how you used our Services, such as how often the Services are used and which features of the Services are used.

Google Services. In addition to other third party analytics service providers and third-party advertisers, we may use Google Analytics, AdWords and AdSense ("Google Services") to collect data about traffic through our Services via advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers. Google may serve advertisements across other websites that you visit based upon your use of our Services, and may also serve our advertisements on other websites. We do not facilitate the merging of Personal Information with Non-Personal Information previously collected through these Google Services. Any data collected will be used in accordance with this privacy policy and Google’s privacy policy located at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.

Third-Party Information Collection. In addition, when you use the Services, certain third parties may use cookies or other automatic information collection technologies to collect information, including Personal Information, about you, your online activities over time and across different websites. We do not control these third parties’ tracking technologies or how they may be used. If you have questions about their data collection practices, you should review the privacy policies of those third parties or contact them directly.

Publicly Posted. If you post information on public areas of the Site (i.e. comments or blog), that information is visible to and may be collected, stored and used by anyone. We recommend you be cautious about giving out Personal Information to others or sharing Personal Information in public or online forums. We are not responsible for the actions of any third parties with whom you share Personal Information.

Information You Voluntarily Provide to Us. If you contact us by phone, email, instant message, live chat, social media, or by some other means, we may keep a record of your contact information (including your name, company name, email, address and phone number) and the correspondence for later reference to help improve our Services. When we send you emails, we may also track whether you open them to figure out how to deliver more helpful emails and improve our Services. Additionally, we may keep a record of any forms, surveys or questionnaires that you voluntarily fill out on our Site or through your use of the Services.

User Accounts. We will collect and store the information you provide to us if you create an account, such as your name, company name, company address, phone number and email address. You do not have to share this information with us, but without it you may not be able to access certain features or participate in certain aspects of the Services.

Financial Information. If you purchase our Services, we may request certain Personal Information to facilitate payment, such as your name, email, phone number, physical address, billing address and the last four digits of your credit card or bank account number. We store only a very limited portion of your credit card information in a manner that is generally permitted by credit card issuers. Stripe, our PCI-compliant payment processor, stores and processes your credit card or other payment information using industry-standard security measures. By making a purchase through the Services, you give us consent to use and provide your financial information as we consider necessary to process the transaction. For additional information on how Stripe secures your payment card information during transmission and storage, please refer to Stripe’s privacy policy located at: <https://stripe.com/us/privacy>. Information Collected Through Use of the Services. If you use our Services, we may collect information about how you use and interact with the Services and the data and information that is collected or provided by you through or in connection with your use of the Services.

### How We Use Your Information

We may use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including Personal Information, to measure usage of the Services, to analyze the effectiveness of our Services, to conduct research, to improve and enhance functionality of the Services, to provide support for the Services and respond to requests and inquiries, to provide you with notices, such as updates or changes that we may make to the Services, and to market and advertise the Services, including through promotional e-mail messages, directly or in partnership with other parties, in accordance with your marketing preferences, and by serving our advertisements on other websites that you visit or use. We may also use this information to offer you targeted advertising in our Services in order to personalize your experience by showing you advertisements for products and services that are more likely to appeal to you (a practice known as behavioral advertising).

We may from time to time aggregate information in certain data analysis, reports, or other interpretations of trends for both internal and external purposes. When aggregating Personal Information, we make sure that the information is not identifiable to any particular user.

If we intend to use any Personal Information in any manner that is not consistent with this Privacy Policy, you will be informed of such anticipated use prior to or at the time at which the Personal Information is collected.

### Disclosure of Your Information

We do not sell, rent, or trade your Personal Information with any third parties except as provided in this Privacy Policy. We may disclose your Personal Information and Non-Personal Information to service providers or other third parties, such as vendors, technical agents, subcontractors and consultants, to perform certain business-related functions that help make the Services and our offerings available and functional, including , but not limited to, design services, installation services, web site hosting, data analysis and metrics services, maintenance and technical services, customer service and support, email delivery services, infrastructure services and to help us in our marketing efforts, including managing and delivering contextual and tailored advertisements. We contractually require these third-party service providers to maintain the confidentiality of the information we share with them, and we contractually require them not use your information for anything other than to provide services on our behalf.

We may also use the information we collect to display advertisements to our advertisers’ target audiences. Even though we do not disclose your Personal Information for these purposes without your consent, if you click on or otherwise interact with an advertisement, the advertiser may assume that you meet its target criteria. We do not actively share Personal Information with third-party advertisers for their direct marketing purposes unless you give us your consent.

In addition, we may disclose your Personal Information and Non-Personal Information to a buyer or other successor as part of a merger, acquisition, change of control or other similar business transfer, to government body or other third party if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a legal obligation, or in specific other cases with your consent.

We may disclose aggregated user statistics and other data with our affiliates, agents and current or prospective business partners. This aggregate information does not personally identify you.

### Choices About How We Collect, Use and Disclose Your Information

We strive to provide you with choices regarding our collection, use and disclosure of the information you provide to us. The mechanisms listed below provide you with control over such collection, use and disclosure:

Marketing Communication. If you do not want us to send you marketing or promotional communications, you can opt-out by clicking the "unsubscribe" link in any such promotional emails, checking the relevant box located on the form on which we collect your data or emailing us at support@timber.io.

Cookies. You have the option to accept or disable cookies at any time through your browsers. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies. For information about managing your privacy and security settings for Flash cookies, see <http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html>. If you choose to disable your cookies, your user experience may be limited.

Google Analytics. You can opt out of tracking by Google Analytics by using Google’s Ads Settings or going to <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

Third-Party Advertising. If you are interested in more information about tailored advertising and your choices to prevent third parties from delivering tailored web advertisements, you may visit the following websites: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> or <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. These opt-out tools are provided by third parties. We do not control or operate these tools or the choices that advertisers and others provide through these tools. Please note that you may still receive advertisements from third parties within our Services even if you opt out of tailored advertising but they will not be based on your activity across unrelated web sites.

Do Not Track Signals. Third parties may keep track of your browsing activities across third party websites. Certain web browsers enable users to activate a "Do Not Track" signal but we do not currently respond to the "Do Not Track" signal or other similar mechanisms.

Notice to California Residents. If you would like to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes, please send an email to support@timber.io.

To request any other changes or information about our collection, use or disclosure of your information, please email us at support@timber.io.

### Accessing and Correcting Your Information

If you wish to access, update, correct or delete any Personal Information in our possession that you have previously submitted via the Services, you may log into your account and make updates. If you wish to make changes not available through your account settings, please contact us at support@timber.io.

### Third Parties; Links to Third Party Sites

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Services. The Services may contain advertisements or links to other web sites not operated or controlled by us (the "Third Party Sites"), and the policies and procedures described in this Privacy Policy do not apply to those Third Party Sites, even if you access them through the Services. The links from the Services do not imply that we endorse or have reviewed the Third Party Sites. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of any Third Party Sites you access so you know how they will use and share your information.

### Children Under the Age of 13

Our Services are intended for users who are 13 years of age and older. If you are under the age of 13, you are not permitted to submit any Personal Information to us. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at support@timber.io.

### Transfer of Personal Information

The Services are based in the United States. If you provide Personal Information to us, you acknowledge and agree that such Personal Information may be transferred from your current location to our offices and servers and the authorized third parties referred to in this Privacy Policy located in the United States.

### Information Applicable to EU Users

The General Data Protection Regulation or "GDPR" gives certain rights to individuals in the European Union in relation to their personal data. As available and except as limited under applicable law, the rights afforded to individuals are:

  * Right of Access - the right to be informed of and request access to the personal data we process about you;
  * Right to Rectification - the right to request that we amend or update your personal data where it is inaccurate or incomplete;
    * Right to Erasure - the right to request that we delete your personal data;
    * Right to Restrict - the right to request that we temporarily or permanently stop processing all or some of your personal data;
  * Right to Object:
    * The right, at any time, to object to us processing your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation;
    * The right to object to your personal data being processed for direct marketing purposes;
  * Right to Data Portability - the right to request a copy of your personal data in electronic format and the right to transmit that personal data for use in another party’s service; and
  * Right not to be subject to Automated Decision-making - the right to not be subject to a decision based solely on automated decision making, including profiling, where the decision would have a legal effect on you or produce a similarly significant effect.

If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, please contact us at support@timber.io.

### Security

We take reasonable steps to protect the Personal Information provided to us from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, no Internet or e-mail transmission is ever fully secure or error free. In particular, e-mail sent to or from the Services may not be secure. Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us via e-mail. Please keep this in mind when disclosing any Personal Information to us via the Internet.

All payment transactions are conducted through our PCI compliant secure payment solutions provider Stripe. We may change our payment processor in the future.

### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework

Timber Technologies, Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. Timber Technologies has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Timber Technologies commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Timber Technologies at: support@timber.io

Timber Technologies has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to TRUSTe, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request> for more information or to file a complaint. The services of TRUSTe are provided at no cost to you.

As a participant in the Privacy Shield, Timber Technologies agrees to be subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Department of Transportation ("DOT") and the U.S. Federal Trade Commission ("FTC"). Accordingly, Timber Technologies may be required to disclose Personal Data to DOT or FTC or other applicable U.S. government agencies including the requirement to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Timber Technologies is not opposed to an individual's election to invoke binding arbitration for the resolution of disputes. Timber Technologies designates the International Centre for Dispute Resolution/American Arbitration Association ("ICDR/AAA") as its alternative dispute resolution provider based in the United States for all matters relating to the Privacy Shield. Accordingly, ICDR/AAA is the independent dispute resolution body designated by Timber Technologies to address complaints and provide appropriate recourse without cost to the individual.

As explained above, we sometimes provide personal information to third parties to perform services on our behalf. If we transfer personal information received under the Privacy Shield to a third party, the third party's access, use, and disclosure of the personal data must also be in compliance with our Privacy Shield obligations, and we will remain liable under the Privacy Shield for any failure to do so by the third party unless we prove we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

### Free Plan Log Deletions

When you sign up for our free plan with 250 MB of storage (“Free Plan”), please be aware that we will only retain the associated logs for three (3) days. After the three (3) days, the logs will be permanently deleted, unless you upgrade to one of our paid Services, which will extend the storage of the logs for up to 3 months. We cannot revive any information once it has been permanently deleted. You can find more information about our pricing plans here: <https://timber.io/pricing>.

### Contact Information

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at support@timber.io.
